Well, uh, to start things off, we're
obviously thrilled to death to have to
get Ruben and to have his family here
and to share this day with him. It's
awesome that you guys could all come.
That's it's really cool. Um, you know,
we put a lot of work into all of our
draft. Um, the players that we're
looking at, it starts a long time ago.
So, I mean, it's hard not to
see this guy on the field when you're
watching him even as a young, you know,
the first time he played there. So, goes
way back, but I'd be lying if I said
yesterday that Todd and I were going in
the draft thinking that there would be a
a good chance of getting Ruben. So, you
know, a lot of times we say surprises
suck, but this surprise did not suck.
Um, so
you know, I said a lot last night, so
I'll just kind of turn it over to coach,
but once again, just very, very excited
to have you and welcome to Tampa.
>> Yes, sir.
>> Uh, you know, it's like Jason said, you
know, we we pick out a few guys that we
don't think is going to make it to 15.
And there were about eight or nine of
them that regardless of position, we
said if these guys end up falling, we're
taking them without a doubt. and we had
our minds made up on another player uh
just because we figured the top eight or
nine guys would be gone and we knew
Ruben was a top 10 pick and he started
falling a little bit and he caught the
15 and we knew it wasn't going any
further and we couldn't be happier
because of the mindset we're trying to
change this year with the type of
players we signed in free agency and the
type of play that he does and the
attitude he plays with and the force he
plays with. It was really a no-brainer
and he fit everything we're trying to do
and get back to from a mental
physicality standpoint and his play
shows that and it was an easy decision.
>> Um, how y'all doing?
I'm excited to be here and let's get it
started.
>> This might be the biggest cheering
section that we've ever seen for a
introductory press conference. How
special is it to have camp family in
Tampa, but then also family that can
very easily drive up from Miami?
>> Uh, I feel like it's a once in a
lifetime kind of thing for me. Um,
something I don't take for granted
knowing that I could have I could have
been across the country somewhere, some
way, somehow and God put me here and I
don't take that for granted cuz I know
my family's here and they going to
support me each in every step of the
way. Um, I only got 10 today, but you
can see about 20 or 30 more rolling in
from time for me being here.
Toby, you look at at Ruben's game. You
can play left side, right side, inside.
How much is that versatility really
appeal to you? Probably be an outside
linebacker for you, but he's got the
capability to do a lot more.
>> It feels a great deal that he can move
up and down the line of scrimmage.
Obviously, he had great coaching in
college and high school. So, it to be
versatile in this game when you're only
allowed to take so many to the game,
it's very important to play at a couple
different positions, and he can do that.
How was there a point where where you
realized that that Ruben was really
possible and viable for 15? I don't know
what what team he went past when you
realized he really could.
>> It was a possibility.
I would say around 13. It was a
possibility. You know, you don't take
any of these things for granted because
people can trade in front of you and
everything else. So, you know, when it
got to 15, I felt better, you know, but
there was a possibility around 13.
Todd, how satisfied are you to have
brought in an edge rusher here with this
15 pick? I mean, how obviously he's
talented? You guys talked about his
skills, but just in general to address
that position so early. How beneficial
would that be for your defense?
>> It's beneficial that we addressed it
with him. Uh there's a bunch of edge
rushers in this draft. Not many can play
like he plays and it plays with the
attitude he plays with and the heavy
hands he plays with and fits the scheme
that we play with as well as the people
that's down there with him that he's
going to be working with.
>> We heard Jason last night talk about
some of the traits that he really found
attractive in him. But for you, what is
it the bend? Is it the lower center of
gravity? What is it about him physically
that makes him such an asset to your
defense? It's his physical style of play
from a mental standpoint and a physical
standpoint. Uh pass rushers come in
different ways and different types and
different sizes. Some are power, some
are speed, some have an arsenal, you
know, some can bend, some can't. He can
do it all. He can do it all. And he
shows that up and down the line of
scrimmage. But he plays with a mentality
and a no no losing mentality at all
times. and he he fights and he plays
with the right kind of attitude that and
mentality that we're trying to bring to
this team.
>> Ruben in talking to Mario and others,
you know, ever since you got there,
you're the first guy, you know, didn't
have to tell you to be early to
meetings, didn't have to tell you to
stay late as you did every day after
practice. Where does that work ethic
come from? Where where does that that
burning desire come from? Um, I think
just uh my family um having that that
standard being put in front of me since
I was adolescence and and a kid. Um
really uh respect to my big brother. Um
he the one that kind of showed me where
football could take me. Uh he probably
don't even know that but that's the
biggest motivator in my life. Um giving
me the constant motivation to get up and
get after uh since I was a little kid
running around at his high school
practice, little kid running around his
college practice. just happy to be there
and there was a lot of lessons I took
from that and now fast forward to today
those lessons is what helped me be who I
am today.
>> When you play with a a nasty edge and a
mean streak where does that come from
and was there a point in time in your
football career where that that switch
was flipped.
>> Uh I think I always had uh that kind of
uh mindset. I feel like I kind of
piggybacks off that question as well.
Just from what I what was put in front
of me um allowed me to be the player I
am today. allowed me to kind of play
with that that that that head on fire
mentality. Um, and just run around
knowing that you never know what play
could be your last. So, I'm always play
I'm always play it like that. Um, I come
in with the game and the mindset that I
don't take anything for granted. So,
when I step on the field, I'm trying to
give them all each and every time.
>> Ruben, you said last night that you were
going to speak with David. Did you have
that conversation with him? How'd that
go? Uh, I haven't yet cuz my phone been
just so crazy. But I got to speak with
Kaja and I just told him, man, I'm I'm
be in this in his ear each and every day
just latching on so I can get as much
help as I possibly can because I'm
trying to come in and help the team out
as much as I possibly can.
>> You were sorry. Uh, Ruben, you wore that
number four really well at Miami. Um,
are you gonna maybe try to apply if
you're never here or is there
>> Um, I've been told it's already it's
it's already took it's busy right now,
but uh, honestly, this is whatever they
end up giving me. Uh, I'm a little
frugal, so all that buying the jersey
stuff off people, I I probably won't do
that. Just take what they give me and go
play some football.
>> And there are a lot of Bucks fans that
are also Miami fans, right? So, like,
how excited are you to kind of maybe
become a fan favorite here early on and
and play in front of them?
>> Uh, very excited. Uh, it's, like I said,
it's opportunity. I don't take for
granted. Um I got to come up here and
see a game. I didn't get to play the
game, but when we play USF, so I'm
familiar with the the stadium, I'll say.
But now this time, I actually get to
strap up and be on the home side of
things and and really just show people
who I am, who I am, and I feel like
they'll fall in love with that, and I'll
fall in love with them.
>> You said that you're the best player in
the draft, best pass rusher, what have
you, but in going to 15, I think that
obviously Jason and Todd were very
surprised you were still there. Does
that put more of a chip that you've
already got pretty big one on your
shoulder anyway, but does that put more
of a chip on your shoulder?
>> Um, I mean, I'll say my mindset is
always to have a bit of edge to me. Uh,
I feel like I'm the best player no
matter what. So, that's kind of what I
feed into. Um, I really don't let any
outside noise dictate that. I just kind
of play with that mindset. I'm going to
get it each and every play. for you
being part of a program. Obviously Miami
has a story history and and so many
people fans in this area talk about like
the glory days of the youth. I know you
guys fell short of your ultimate goal,
but to bring the program to where it was
like what did that mean for you like
personally to be part of that culture
change?
>> It meant a lot. Um especially for I know
all the guys that was there throwing
those five and seven, seven and six
seasons. Uh it meant even more to us
because we was there when it was ugly.
We didn't just hop on the bandwagon when
it was pretty. Um, so to actually build
something from the ground up, I feel
like it means a little bit more cuz
Chris, he always says like he never
wanted to say the US was back, but he
was here. And that's a that's a mindset
I have is we just doing what we do. We
play football how we play and we going
to reap the the rewards of our success.
>> How did that force you to grow as a
leader in and again being part of that
culture change?
>> Uh, it was it was challenging at first.
Um, cuz just me, I'm more of a a quieter
guy. Uh so understanding that is more
than being uh by example kind of leader.
Uh I have to be vocal at times. I'm
still a little hesitant what I say
because I feel like the the more
selective you are with your words, the
more the more weight it holds. Um so I
kind of uh choose when it's the right
time. But at all times I'm going to be a
leader, whether that's being by example
or vocal.
He's a special talent, but what's the
biggest adjustment for a guy coming from
college even though he's dominated at
the highest level to the NFL at that?
>> It's really just the length of the
season. You know, they we play 17
regular plus three preseason games than
you got playoffs. And that's probably
quite a bit more than they play in
college. And as long as you come in in
shape, and I'm sure he will. And he's
probably already in shape, he'll be
fine. It shouldn't be much of an
adjustment.
Ruby, I know players are motivated
anytime you don't get picked by a team,
but to be from Miami, to have starred at
Miami, to have the Dolphins make another
pick, how much will that motivate you?
>> Uh, I mean, I feel like won't change
anything. Um, my motivation is myself. I
always want to be the best player on the
field no matter what. Uh, no outside
factors going to kind of weigh into
that. And I'm going to play the game
just as if I was playing anybody else.
Um, and that's with all my effort. And
when you see that, people gonna see the
kind of player I am.
>> Just so you know, the States passed on.
>> Yeah, they did.
>> Something that was talked about
yesterday is just how much your passion
for football sticks out. Has it always
been like that or was there a moment
that really for you?
>> Ah, um, it kind of developed a little
bit more when I was 13. I really didn't
like football. I thought I was going to
be a basketball player growing up,
especially watching LeBron. He was in
Miami at the time. So, I thought I was
going to be a basketball player. But
after uh I felt like I stopped going, it
just showed me that football going to be
the thing for me. And um that's when I
felt like I really starting to
understand what football could do and
how to really like take pride in my game
and what it really really means to be a
defensive lineman. And ever since then,
the sky's has been the limit.
>> Jason was asked about your arm length
last night. He said rather defiantly
that Mike Tyson also had shorter arms,
too. And I believe in an interview with
my friend Cameron Wolf, he would also
mention Mike Tyson. he came up. Is he is
he some type of an inspiration for you
athletically?
>> Uh I don't know if people know but I
really love boxing and so uh that's a
person I feel like very vicious and
violent and I feel like my game is
vicious and violent. So it's some sort
of comparison of mindset things uh I
feel like we have in common and that's
just uh I feel like it's a a great
comparison.
Speaking of competition, battles,
looking forward to going against some
guys in training camp like a Tristan
Wors, a Luke Geti.
>> Uh, for sure. Uh, the first thing I was
thinking of was I could get better each
and every day knowing I'm going against
the best of the best. Uh, Tristan, I
feel like he going to give me the best
the best looks I possibly can. I'm going
do my best to give him the best looks he
possibly could get. Uh, because one, I
know that that's a great caliber of
player and I'm understanding that I
ain't sharp as I am. That's what we was
built on in college and that's my same
mindset to come in and do the same thing
at this level. Give him my all so I can
get get all his from him.
>> What are some words of advice you have
for young guys that want to be where you
are today?
>> Uh to keep working. Um because nobody
can never tell you no. It's never knows.
It's not yet. Um nobody determines what
you can and can't accomplish and and no
matter what the situation no matter what
the situation is, you always determine
the outcome.
Ruben, you learned a lot from Jason
Taylor in your time here at Miami. Is
there a top takeaway? What's what's the
one thing top of mind that he taught you
that he still?
>> I can say uh like patience. Um and that
really a lot like relate on to not only
but life but football. I used to kind of
tense up a little bit if I felt like
games weren't really going my way. And
so he uh instilled the mindset in me to
rather just let things come to me and
let let the game just flow and like my
instincts just took over.
>> How much did it help you to and how much
did you learn and learn from each other?
You're able to play with a guy like me
in Miami.
>> Uh that was a tremendous amount of help.
Um coming into college was my mentor,
somebody that took me under his wing and
uh really introduced me to what college
football is like. Uh, and I was able to
really get one-on-one coaching because
he was hurt that first year, my freshman
year. And, um, ever since then, we just
been flourishing and getting better each
and every day. And come fast forward to
this year, it was more of a still it's
still a big boral relationship, but more
like a peer right now. Um, and we was
able just to really bounce off each
other withformational competition,
anything we really wanted to do.
Anything
>> else?
Thank y'all.